{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which band has Robert Smith as its lead singer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Can The Can","incorrectAnswers":["Do The Do","See The Sea","Dance The Dance"],"question":"What Was Suzi Quatro's First Hit In 1973?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Backstroke","incorrectAnswers":["Breaststroke","Front Crawl","Butterfly"],"question":"Which Swimming Stroke Is The First Leg Of The Medley Relay Race?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You know how to whistle, don't you, Steve? You just put your lips together and blow.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\"","\"Is it safe?\"","\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'To Have and Have Not'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Midsummer Night's Dream'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Attila","incorrectAnswers":["Genghis Khan","Alexander the Great","Napoleon Bonaparte"],"question":"Which famous military leader was defeated in the Battle of the Catalaunian Plains in 451 A.D.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Edinburgh","incorrectAnswers":["Aberdeen","Glasgow","Cardiff"],"question":"What is the capital of Scotland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Steeple Chase","incorrectAnswers":["Marathon","Triathlon","Iron Man"],"question":"What Type Of Race Got Its Name From A Short Dash Between 2 Churches?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Martin Luther King Jr ","incorrectAnswers":["Mahatma Gandhi","Florence Nightingale","Mother Theresa"],"question":"Who received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964 for his civil rights leadership?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Twilight","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Harry Potter","Percy Jackson & the Olympians"],"question":"In which book series would you find the character 'Jacob Black'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"A Button","incorrectAnswers":["A Carrot","Snow","An Icicle"],"question":"According to the lyrics of the famous Christmas song, what was Frosty The Snowman's nose made from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Syria?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Butcher","Wizard","Monk"],"question":"What type of position does Hamlet hold in the Shakespeare play?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ordo ab chao","incorrectAnswers":["Qui totum vult orduris perdit","Melita, domi adsum","Nil volentibus arduum"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Out of chaos, comes order'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lamprophony","incorrectAnswers":["Doodle Sack","Donkey Engine","Lackadaisical"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'loudness and clarity of enunciation'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Horilka","incorrectAnswers":["Schnapps","Grappa","Waragi"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Ukraine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Fat Man","incorrectAnswers":["Big Boy","Bonnie Lad","Chunky Joe"],"question":"What was the name given to the atom bomb that was dropped on Hiroshima?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1969","incorrectAnswers":["1967","1965","1963"],"question":"In What Year Did Neil Armstrong First Step Foot On The Moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Let's Spend the Night Together","incorrectAnswers":["Blinded","Whiskey in a Jar","Sea of Love"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by the Rolling Stones, was later covered by David Bowie?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canberra","incorrectAnswers":["Sydney","Melbourne","Perth"],"question":"What is the capital city of Australia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oahu","incorrectAnswers":["Kauai","Hawaii","Maui"],"question":"On what island is Pearl Harbour?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Herring ","incorrectAnswers":["Cod","Tuna","Salmon"],"question":"What Type Of Fish Is A Kipper","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Lumiere Brothers","incorrectAnswers":["The Warner Brothers","The Cannes Brothers","The Canal Brothers"],"question":"Who Opened The First Cinema In Paris In 1895?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Josh Brolin","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Douglas","Ben Kingsley","Kiefer Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Avengers: Endgame and No Country for Old Men?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saturn","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Mars","Uranus"],"question":"What is the name of the second-largest planet in our solar system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cher","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Gaga","Sia","Madonna"],"question":"Whose Real Name Is 'Cherilyn Sarkisian La Pier'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Forrest Gump","incorrectAnswers":["Rocky","Scarface","Indiana Jones"],"question":"In what movie does the main character have a friend called Bubba Blue who dreams of opening up his own shrimping business?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Malaysia","incorrectAnswers":["Iran","Japan","Bhutan"],"question":"Nasi Lemak is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tartare Sauce ","incorrectAnswers":["Mayonnaise","Hollandaise Sauce","Bernaise Sauce"],"question":"Which sauce is made with mayonnaise and chopped pickled gherkin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Chile","Sweden"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1970 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mad Max: Fury Road","incorrectAnswers":["Warrior","City Lights","Casino"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'In a post-apocalyptic wasteland, a woman rebels against a tyrannical ruler.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","The United Kingdom","New Zealand"],"question":"Of which country did Robert Menzies become Prime Minister in April 1939?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pop art","incorrectAnswers":["Dadaism","Surrealism","Cubism"],"question":"Which 1950's art movement presented a challenge to traditions of fine art by including imagery from popular and mass culture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tampa Bay Lightening","incorrectAnswers":["Tampa Bay Steelers","Tampa Bay Seahawks","Tamba Bay Wizards"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Tampa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Marley","Bobby Brown","Robert Plant"],"question":"Whose real name is Robert Zimmerman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Blue","Purple"],"question":"Which of these colors is traditionally associated with Christmas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dinar","incorrectAnswers":["Lira","Rial","Shekel"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for Jordan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Salyut 1","incorrectAnswers":["Skylab","Mir","ISS"],"question":"What is the name of the first space station launched into orbit in 1971?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ringo Starr","incorrectAnswers":["John Lennon","George Harrison","Paul McCartney"],"question":"Who wore the pink uniform on the cover of Sgt. Pepper's?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The y in 'yellow'","incorrectAnswers":["The p in 'pin'","The t in 'train'","The sh in 'shop'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of an approximant sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Athlete's foot","incorrectAnswers":["Ringworm","Jock itch","Yeast infection"],"question":"What common fungal infection is also known as tinea pedis and is highly contagious?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Richter Scale ","incorrectAnswers":["The Geiger Scale","The Scoville Scale","The Bristol Scale"],"question":"What Scale Is Used To Measure The Intensity Of An Earthquake","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Richard III","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Macbeth","Othello"],"question":"\"Now is the winter of our discontent\" is a line from which Shakespearian play?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Joseph Lister","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Faraday","Benny Russell","Franz Jacob"],"question":"Which surgeon pioneered the use of sterilisation and antiseptic surgery?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ethology","incorrectAnswers":["Zoology","Anthropology","Neuroscience"],"question":"Which science studies animal behaviour in natural habitats ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"prehistoric metaphytes ","incorrectAnswers":["ants","the ecology of any individual species","the writings and practices of historians"],"question":"What is Paleobotany the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rhode Island ","incorrectAnswers":["Maine","Vermont","Hawaii"],"question":"Which Is The Smallest State In The USA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Suleiman I","incorrectAnswers":["Osman I","Mehmed II","Murad IV"],"question":"Who was the longest-reigning sultan of the Ottoman Empire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jacques-Louis David","incorrectAnswers":["René Magritte","Vincent van Gogh","‎Pablo Picasso"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Napoleon crossing the Alps\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Babe Ruth","incorrectAnswers":["Ian Botham","Jay Rodriguez","Brian Lara"],"question":"Who wore a cabbage leaf under his cap?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lucy Maud Montgomery","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Munro","Lewis Carroll","Margaret Atwood"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Anne of Green Gables'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The structure of cells","incorrectAnswers":["Human emotions","Feces","Electricity"],"question":"What is Cytomorphology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Isis","incorrectAnswers":["Set","Ammit","Horus"],"question":"In Egyptian mythology, who was Horus' mother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gong","incorrectAnswers":["French Horn","Bagpipe","Fife"],"question":"Which of these is a percussion instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Douglas Adams","incorrectAnswers":["John Wong","Terry Pratchett","Michel Palin"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Smokin' in the Boys Room","incorrectAnswers":["Me And Mrs. Jones","Mickey","Don't Wanna Fall in Love"],"question":"Brownsville Station had a one hit wonder in 1973 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen","incorrectAnswers":["Viborg","Amsterdam","Stockholm"],"question":"The Little Mermaid is found in the harbour of which city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J.R.R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Roald Dahl","George R.R. Martin","Brandon Sanderson"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Hobbit\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1789","incorrectAnswers":["1689","1889","1989"],"question":"In What Year Did The French Revolution Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Nevermind'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dream Theater","incorrectAnswers":["Jars of Clay","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American progressive metal band released the studio album 'Metropolis Pt. 2: Scenes from a Memory'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","North Macedonia","China"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three equal vertical bands of green white and orange.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"In an air crash","incorrectAnswers":["Poisoned","Shot","Attacked by a bear"],"question":"How Did UN Secretary General Dag Hammarskjoeld Die In September 1961?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Jeannie C. Riley","incorrectAnswers":["Quiet Riot","Michael Sembello","Nena"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1968 with Harper Valley Pta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hamburg","incorrectAnswers":["Barcelona","Lyon","Zürich"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Germany?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Microsoft","Google","Linux"],"question":"Who Make Macintosh Computers?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Lady Tremaine","incorrectAnswers":["The Evil Queen","Ursula","Maleficent"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in Cinderella?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic Ocean","Arctic Ocean","Indian Ocean"],"question":"What ocean is found along the East Coast of Asia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Oxygen","incorrectAnswers":["Hydrogen","Dark Matter","Higgs Bosons"],"question":"Of what is 98% of the weight of water made?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Calf","incorrectAnswers":["A Codling","A Fry","A Cygnet"],"question":"What would you call a baby hippopotamus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1963","incorrectAnswers":["1942","1949","1956"],"question":"When did Martin Luther King give his “I Have a Dream” speech?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Spotlight","incorrectAnswers":["Django Unchained","Trainspotting","Catch Me If You Can"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The story of how the scandal of child molestation within the Boston Catholic church was uncovered.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","Syria","Bangladesh"],"question":"Which of these countries has yellow on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kenya","incorrectAnswers":["Yemen","Eritrea","Seychelles"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Somalia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Escalade","incorrectAnswers":["Focus","911","Seven"],"question":"Which of these models of car is made by Cadillac?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Indy 500","incorrectAnswers":["The Daytona 500","The Monaco Grand Prix","The 24 Hours of Le Mans"],"question":"In which race did Janet Guthrie become the first woman to compete in 1977?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kit","incorrectAnswers":["A Joey","An Eaglet","A Lava"],"question":"What would you call a baby ferret?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Antennae","incorrectAnswers":["Ears","Noses","Tongues"],"question":"What do most butterflies use to smell?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Clarets","incorrectAnswers":["The Seasiders","The Red Devils","The Cherries"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Burnley FC?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Leader of Soviet Communist Party who pursued reform - perestroika and glasnost to open Eastern Europe to democracy.","incorrectAnswers":["Developed the world's first vaccine (for smallpox).","Explorer, first European to reach India and establish a route for imperialism.","Influential Christian saint and writer, who shaped much of Western Christian thought."],"question":"Which of the following describes Mikhail Gorbachev?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Grant Wood","incorrectAnswers":["Georges Seurat","Vincent van Gogh","Peter Paul Rubens"],"question":"Which artist painted \"American Gothic\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Laos","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1999","incorrectAnswers":["1993","1996","2002"],"question":"The Matrix was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Trivial Pursuit","incorrectAnswers":["Life","Risk","Checkers"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must move pieces around a board and answer questions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"birds","incorrectAnswers":["myths","the attribute (of a word) of being self descriptive","the atmosphere"],"question":"What is Ornithology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["India","Japan","South Korea"],"question":"Which country includes the provinces of Shaanxi and Jiangsu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"homemade","incorrectAnswers":["Butterflies","Small thimbles","Twins"],"question":"The pasta casarecce has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Portuguese","incorrectAnswers":["Hindi","Berber","Gujarati"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in Angola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Duolingo","incorrectAnswers":["Japan Airlines","Giorgio Armani","Slazenger"],"question":"Which of these brands has a owl on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tajikistan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the album 'In Utero'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Earnshaw","incorrectAnswers":["Heathcliffe","Darcy","Bingby"],"question":"What is the surname of Cathy in \"Wuthering Heights\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"10","incorrectAnswers":["6","4","2"],"question":"How many legs does a crab have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["W.A.S.P.","Paramore","Alice in Chains"],"question":"Which British-American rock band released the studio album 'Rumours'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Hasta la vista, baby.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","\"Made it, Ma! Top of the world!\"","\"Attica! Attica!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Terminator 2: Judgment Day'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Oklahoma","incorrectAnswers":["Kansas","Missouri","California"],"question":"Which US state in 1907 was the last to declare Christmas a legal holiday?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Strand pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Ribbon pasta","Tubular pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is bigoli?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jafar","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula","Hades","Maleficent"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in Aladdin?","difficulty":"medium"},